Guide to the Sussex Correspondence
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Sussex correspondence
1812-1841
OSB MSS 58
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.8
(2 boxes)
Letters to Augustus Frederick, mainly concerning the Duke's library and his literary interests; many originally accompanied presentation copies of works by the authors. Also letters requesting financial patronage, personal favors, or the Duke's participation in learned societies.
Augustus Frederick, Prince, Duke of Sussex, 1773-1843
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
AUGUSTUS FREDERICK, DUKE OF SUSSEX (1773-1843)
Augustus Frederick, Duke of Sussex, was the ninth child of King George III and Queen Charlotte. Educated on the Continent, he met and married Lady Augusta Murray secretly in 1793. George III declared the marriage invalid in accordance with the Royal Marriage Act of 1772, although the couple remained together for some years and had two children.
In 1801 Augustus Frederick was granted the title of Baron Arklow, Earl of Inverness and Duke of Sussex. He supported the abolition of the slave trade, Catholic emancipation, civil liberties for Jews and Dissenters, and Parliamentary reform. He became Grand Master of the Freemasons in 1811; was elected President of the Society of Arts in 1816; and served as President of the Royal Society from 1830 to 1838.
The Duke was an avid book collector, often bidding in competition with Sir Thomas Phillipps, and his library eventually contained over 50,000 volumes, including more than 1,000 editions of the Bible and many Hebrew manuscripts. In 1817 he appointed Thomas Joseph Pettigrew his surgeon; Pettigrew came to serve as his librarian for some years and published the first volumes of the Bibliotheca Sussexiana in 1827. The two men were estranged as a result of the Duke's embarrassingly narrow victory in the Royal Society elections of 1830, a contest that Pettigrew had persuaded the Duke to enter, but the next volumes of the Bibliotheca nevertheless appeared in 1839.
Augustus Frederick remarried late in life, to Cecelia, ninth daughter of the Earl of Arran and widow of Sir George Buggins; there were no children of this marriage. The Duke died of erysipelas on April 21, 1843.
Scope and Contents
The Sussex Correspondence consists of over 130 letters to Augustus Frederick, Duke of Sussex, and approximately 30 letters addressed to his surgeon and librarian, Thomas Joseph Pettigrew. The letters, arranged alphabetically by author, span the dates 1812-1841 and document the Duke's book collecting as well as some of his patronage and charitable activities.
Letters from many correspondents originally accompanied presentation copies of works they had authored, including those by George Man Burrows, Bishop Samuel Butler, William Collyer, Thomas Agar Holland, George Skene Keith, César Moreau, William Müller, Sir Nicholas Harris Nicholas, Edward O'Reilly, Charles Hippolyte Paravey, George Petrie, George Skinner, William Smith, and Benjamin Lewis Vulliamy. Other letters seek the Duke's patronage for recent or proposed publications. Thomas Christopher Banks sought to sell a copy of his Stemmata Anglicana, for example, while P. Lauder solicited funds for the publication of his "Observations on the Defective State of British Timber", and Francis Nugent Macnamara requested a subscription from the Duke for his poem "The Liberator."
Some correspondence is more generally concerned with the Duke's library and literary interests, including requests to visit the library, offers to sell incunabula and manuscripts, and gifts of volumes on subjects of interest to the Duke, such as the gift of a catalogue of Egyptian antiquities in Turin from the chargé d'affaires of Sardinia, and the presentation by John Wylie, President of the Maitland Club, of a set of that club's antiquarian publications.
In addition, there are letters requesting financial assistance, patronage appointments, and small personal favors, some written by those in need of assistance, and others written in their behalf by friends and acquaintances of Augustus Frederick; correspondence concerning his membership in various learned societies; and a letter by the first earl of Donoughmore on resolutions recently approved by the Grand Lodges.
Authors and patrons; Benevolence; Benefactors -- Great Britain; Augustus Frederick, Prince, Duke of Sussex, 1773-1843; Pettigrew, Thomas Joseph, 1791-1865
- Correspondence, Series I
  - "A"
    Scope and Contents
    Abinger, James Scarlett, Baron, 1769-1844
    - ALS to the Earl of Sheffield, London, [after 1837] (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Académie des sciences, arts et belles-lettres de Dijon. 2 letters in French to the Duke of Sussex, signed by Maillard de Chambrune, Dijon, 1828-30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Election of the Duke of Sussex as an honorary member.
    - Alexander, Mr.
      - AL in third person to Mr. Conroy, Great Yarmouth, n.y. Nov 7 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Anson, Anna to the Duke of Sussex, n.y. Jun 17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Augustus Frederick, Duke of Sussex, 1773-1843
      - ALS to Karl II, Duke Brunswick, Kensington Palace, 1827 Jul 11 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Memorandum (copy, partial) on William Salisbury, [n.p.] (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "B"
    - Badham, Charles, 1780-1845. AL to the Duke of Sussex, [n.p.], [1830] (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Baird, George Husband, 1761-1840
      - AL to T. J. Pettigrew, Parliament Street, 1830 Aug 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - AL to the Duke of Sussex, London, 1830 Aug 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Banks, Thomas Christopher, 1765-1854. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Dormant Peerage Office, 1825 Mar 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Written on blank page of prospectus for Stemmata Anglicana. Sales letter for his new volume.
    - Barréres, B. AL (copy) in French to the Duke of Sussex, Brussels, 1822 Mar 7 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Beresford, William Carr Beresford, 1st viscount, 1768-1854. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 1814 Feb 6 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Berkeley, Mary (Cole) Berkeley, countess of, 1767-1844. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Cranford House, 1814 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Asks justice as to validity of her marriage.
    - Blackwood, Sir Henry, 1770-1832. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Admiralty House, 1830 Jun 4 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Blair, Robert
      - ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Edinburgh, 1830 Jul 24 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, Edinburgh, 1830 Aug 10 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Blair, Robert, 1760-1837. AL to T. J. Pettigrew, Edinburgh, 1823 Aug 23 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bradfield, Henry Joseph Steele, 1805-1852. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, London, 1841 Aug 28 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Buckingham and Chandos, Richard Temple Nugent Brydges Chandos, 1st Duke of, 1776-1839. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Stow, 1827 Jun 3 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Burrows, George Man, 1771-1846
      - AL to the Duke of Sussex, 10 Montague St, 1828 Aug 2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
        Sends copy of his new book.
      - ALS to R. J. Pettigrew, 10 Montague St, 1829 Oct 24 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Butler, Samuel, Bishop of Lichfield, 1774-1839
      - AL to T. J. Pettigrew, Shrewsbury, 1817 Jun 24 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        Visits library of Duke of Sussex. Sends book.
      - AL to the Duke of Sussex, Shrewsbury, 1825 Mar 28 (Box 1, Folder 23)
        Sends a copy of the funeral sermon.
  - "C"
    - Cambridge, Adolphus Frederick, Duke of, 1774-1850. AL to unidentified recipient, Cambridge House, [1849?] Jul 2 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Concerning assistance for Mrs. Gautier.
    - Camporese, Violante Giustiniani. ALS in Italian to the Duke of Sussex, Golden Square, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Thanks for patronage.
    - Cassan, Stephen Hyde, 1789-1841. ALS to [T. J. Pettigrew], Mere, 1828 Mar 1 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Chetwynd, Richard Chetwynd, 5th viscount, 1757-1821. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, Whitehall, 1820 Jun 9 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Committee on preparation for coronation.
    - Chevalier, Thomas, 1767-1824. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, South Audley St., 1823 Aug 14 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Requests support for Mr. Sweatman.
    - Clifford, of Chudleigh, Charles Clifford, 6th baron, 1759-1831. AL to the Duke of Sussex, Portman Square, 1814 Mar 23 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      Sends Rules of Associated R.C. Charities.
    - Coigny, duc de. ALS in French to the Duke of Sussex, Spanish Place, 1814 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Collyer, William Bengo, 1782-1854. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Peckham, 1829 Sep 7 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      Sends volumes of sermons.
  - "D"
    - Disney, John, 1779-1857. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, [n.p.], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Donoughmore, Richard Hely-Hutchinson, 1st earl of, 1756-1825. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Knocklofty, 1814 Nov 2 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Approval of certain resolutions by Grand Lodges.
    - Doodley, D. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Cavendish St., 1829 Jun 3 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Dover, George James Welbore Agar-Ellis, 1st baron, 1797-1833. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Spring Garden, 1827 Apr 11 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Drury, Henry Joseph Thomas, 1778-1841. 2 ALS to an unnamed recipient, Harrow, 1829, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "E"
    Eardley, Sampson Eardley, 1st baron, 1745-1824
    - ALS to [H.F. Stephenson?], Grosvenor Street, 1813 Jul 8 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Grosvenor Street, 1822 Apr 30 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Egremont, George O'Brien Wyndham, 3rd earl of, 1751-1837. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Grosvenor Place, 1819 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      Success of Mr. Pettigrew in election.
    - Einsiedel, Henry. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 108 Jermyn St., 1826 Apr 6 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      About one of the Duke's Bibles.
    - Elizabeth, Princess, Landgravine of Hesse-Harding, 1770-1840. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, Buckingham House, [1831] May 6 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Elrington, Lord. AL to Mr. Stephenson, No. Audley Street, [1823] Feb 26 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Elwin, Robert Fountain, 1784-1853. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Norwich, 1829 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "F"
    - Fairman, W. Blennerhassett. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, British Hotel, 1830 Jan 16 (Box 1, Folder 44)
      Seeks election as Secretary of the Humane Society. With a printed letter of solicitation and a clipping about his son.
    - Fauche Borel, Louis de, 1762-1829. ALS in French to the Duke of Sussex, 33 Haymarket, 1822 Aug 9 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Fisher, John, bishop of Salisbury, 1748-1825
      - ALS to an unnamed recipient, Seymour Street, 1812 Jun 27 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - 2 LS to the Duke of Sussex, Upper Seymour Street, 1813, 1814 (Box 1, Folder 47)
        Summons to chapter meetings of the Order of the Garter.
    - Fitzwilliam, Charles William Wentworth Fitzwilliam, 3rd earl, 1786-1857
      - ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Milton, 1822 May 2 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - AL to Mr. Stephenson, Grosvenor Square, n.y. Mar 8 (Box 1, Folder 49)
        Will obey the Duke's commands on the 12th.
    - Francklin, William, 1763-1839
      - ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, Bloomsbury, 1827 Jan 3 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - AL to the Duke of Sussex, Bath, 1830 Aug 3 (Box 1, Folder 51)
        Seeks appointment in the British Museum, with 2 page letter of transmittal to T. J. Pettigrew.
  - "G"
    - Gaillard, marquis de. Memorandum in French for the Duke of Sussex, [Marseilles], [1817?] (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Genovese, Vicente. LS to T. J. Pettigrew, 37 Great Windmill St., 1824 Jul 8 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Giles, John, ALS to the Earl of Stanhope, King's Row, 1839 Apr 15 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      Wishes to visit the library of the Duke of Sussex.
    - Glasgow, George Boyle, 4th Earl of, 1765?-1843. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Camden Hill, 1830 Aug 4 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Gorham, George Cornelius, 1787-1857. AL to the Duke of Sussex, Clapham Common, 1826 Mar 18 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      Permission to visit the Duke's library.
    - Gray, Robert, Bishop of Bristol, 1762-1834. 2 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, Great George St., 1829 May 12, 14 (Box 1, Folder 57)
      His visit to the library of the Duke of Sussex. Sends books.
    - Great Britain. Lord Chamberlain. 2 letters to the Duke of Sussex, Lord Chamberlain's Office, 1817, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Great Britain. Parliament, 1826. House of Lords Summons to the Duke of Sussex, House of Lords, 1826 Feb 9 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Grec, Nicolo Chiefala, Captain. Letters copy in French to the Duke of Sussex, n.p., 1824 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Grindley, P. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, North Bank, 1829 Aug 20 (Box 1, Folder 61)
      Accepts dinner invitation.
    - Guilford, Susan (Coutts) North, baroness, countess of, 1797-1884. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Picadilly, 1830 Feb 13 (Box 1, Folder 62)
      Asks nomination for a boy to London Orphan Asylum.
    - Gurney, William Brodie, 1777-1855. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, [n.p.], [1829] (Box 1, Folder 63)
      Seeks aid for Mr. Newman.
  - "H"
    - Hardenberg, Frederick, Count. ALS in French to the Duke of Sussex, Berlin, 1817 Feb 15 (Box 1, Folder 64)
      Discusses proposed travel to England.
    - Holland, Thomas Agar, 1803-1888. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Oving, 1826 Dec 2 (Box 1, Folder 65)
      Sends a volume.
    - Hurtado, Mr. Letter to the Duke of Sussex, London, 1825 Apr 14 (Box 1, Folder 66)
      2 volumes of Memoirs of the Columbian Secretaries of State.
    - Hutton, J. H. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, Stockbridge, 1830 Jun 14 (Box 1, Folder 67)
      He has a Vulgate of 1567 and a New Testament of 1543.
  - "J"
    - Jehring, C. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Little Charles St., 1829 Feb 9 (Box 1, Folder 68)
      Seeks to dedicate The German Speaker to the Duke.
  - "K"
    - Karl Friedrich August Wilhelm, Duke of Brunswick-Luneberg, 1804-1873. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Brunswick, 1827 Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 69)
      Complains of Count Münster and Schmidt-Phiseldeck.
    - Keith, George Skene, 1752-1823. 2 ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Keith-Hall, 1817 Jan, Feb (Box 1, Folder 70)
      Sends pamphlets on weights and measures.
    - Kelly, Patrick, 1756-1842. AL to the Duke of Sussex, Finsbury Square, 1816 Jun 6 (Box 1, Folder 71)
      Answers to queries on relative values of income.
  - "L"
    - Lackington, George, 1768-1844. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, Egyptian Hall, [1821] (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Lascelles, Rowley, 1771-1841. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, St. James's Park, 1830 Aug 2 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Lauder, P., 2 ALS to the Duke of Sussex, London, 1830, 1831 (Box 1, Folder 74)
      Seeking patronage for his book, "Observations on the Defective State of British Timber." Written on copies of the prospectus.
    - Leahy, Edward Daniel, 1791-1875. AL to the Duke of Sussex, 30 Old Bond St., 1826 Feb 15 (Box 1, Folder 75)
      An engraving from his portrait proposed.
    - Lee, John, 1779-1859
      - ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Edinburgh, 1824 Apr 20 (Box 1, Folder 76)
        Sends copy of a pamphlet.
      - ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Bloomsbury, 1825 Jan 13 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Leleux, A. ALS in French to the Duke of Sussex, Calais, 1829 Feb 7 (Box 1, Folder 78)
      Seeks assistance.
    - Linley, William, 1771-1835. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Furnival's Inn, n.y. Mar 23 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Lopez, Pablo. LS in the third person to the Duke of Sussex, Somers Town, 1826 Sep 13 (Box 1, Folder 80)
      Refugee seeks financial aid.
  - "M"
    - McKonachie, Alexander. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 21 Regent Street, 1830 Dec 9 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Macnamara, Francis Nugent. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, London, 1830 May 24 (Box 2, Folder 82)
      Seeks subscription for his poem "The Liberator."
    - Mande, John. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Moor House, 1826 Feb 14 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Manners Sutton, Charles, Archbishop of Canterbury, 1755-1828. LS to the Duke of Sussex, 15 Duke St. W. (Box 2, Folder 84)
      Report on Society for Promoting the Enlargement and Building of Churches and Chapels.
    - Mansfield, Charles James. AL to the Duke of Sussex, Canonbury, 1829 Feb 26 (Box 2, Folder 85)
      Would collect for copy of J. P. Vernon's Sermons.
    - Mars, P. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, High St., Manchester Sq., [1828] (Box 2, Folder 86)
      Seeks a subscription.
    - Martin, Robert Montgomery, 1803?-1868. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 147 Strand, 1830 Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 87)
      Proposals for a London Irish newspaper.
    - Moreau, César. ALS in French to the Duke of Sussex, London, 1824 Aug 21 (Box 2, Folder 88)
      Sends copy of Commerce de la Grande Brétagne.
    - Mudge, William, 1762-1820. LS to the Duke of Sussex, Royal Military Academy, 1817 Feb 12 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Muleun, ---. ALS in French to the Duke of Sussex, n.p., 1829 Sep 30 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Müller, William, d. 1846. 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, Hanover, 1822-30 (Box 2, Folder 91)
      On books for the library of the Duke of Sussex. With an essay on the cosmosphere, an improved geographical globe.
    - Münster-Ledenburg, Ernest Friedrich Herbert Reichsgraf von, 1766-1839
      - 2 ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Putney Hill and Grosvenor Place, 1827, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 92)
      - AL to the Duke of Sussex, [n.p.], 1830 May 26 (Box 2, Folder 93)
        On the pendulum presented by the Duke to Göttingen Observatory.
    - Münter, Friedrick, Bishop of Sealand. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Copenhagen, 1829 Aug 8 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - "N"
    - Nathan, Isaac, 1791?-1864. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Clapham, 1830 Sep 6 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Niblock, Joseph White. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Hitchin, 1828 Sep 10 (Box 2, Folder 96)
      Seeks to increase his collection of Forms of Prayer.
    - Nicolas, Sir Nicholas Harris, 1799-1848
      - ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 23 Tavistock Place, 1829 Mar 20 (Box 2, Folder 97)
      - ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 23 Tavistock Place, 1830 Aug 6 (Box 2, Folder 98)
        Sends privately printed works.
  - "O"
    - Oldoini, Marquis. AL in third person in French to the Duke of Sussex, 5 Berkeley Square, 1832 Sep 20 (Box 2, Folder 99)
      Chargé d'affaires of Sardinia wishes to present a catalog of Egyptian antiquities in the royal museum of Turin.
    - Oliver, Robert Dudley, 1766-1850. AL to the Duke of Sussex, 5 Maddox Street, 1830 Aug 3 (Box 2, Folder 100)
      Requests an audience.
    - O'Reilly, Edward, d. 1829. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Dublin Castle, 1825 Aug 20 (Box 2, Folder 101)
      Sends his prize essay on the Brehan Laws.
    - Ousley, Sir Gore, 1st Bart., 1770-1844. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 49 Upper Grosvenor St., 1830 Jun 19 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - "P"
    - Palmetta, comte de. ALS in French to the Duke of Sussex, [n.p.], 1817 Jul 23 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Paravey, Charles Hippolyte, 1787-1857. AL and ALS in French to the Duke of Sussex, 1830 Jun 4, 8 (Box 2, Folder 104)
      Presents his Essai sur Hieroglyphiques.
    - Parry, John, 1776-1851.
      - 4 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew; v.p., 1831-32 (Box 2, Folder 105)
        Musical topics.
      - ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 17 Tavistock Street, 1831 Jun 23 (Box 2, Folder 106)
        Invitation to the Melodists Club dinner.
    - Pasley, Sir Charles William, 1780-1861. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Chatham, 1831 Jun 11 (Box 2, Folder 107)
      Presents a paper on weights and measures.
    - Passarant, J. H. de Speyr. ALS in French to the Duke of Sussex, Paris, 1829 Dec 24 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Penn, William, 1776-1845. ALS to Lord Ferrers (later Lord Townshend), 7 Lambeth Road, [1830] Jan 24 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Petrie, George, 1789-1866. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Dublin, 1831 Apr 25 (Box 2, Folder 110)
      Sends essay on MS of the Annals of the Four Masters.
    - Picken, Andrew, 1788-1833. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Pimlico, 1831 Jan 19 (Box 2, Folder 111)
      Seeks patronage and employment.
    - Prescot, Bartholomew. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Liverpool, 1831 Feb 24 (Box 2, Folder 112)
      On his Remarks on the Architecture....of Palmyra. Accompanied by ALS to C. W. Williams Wynn, 1831 Feb 24.
    - Pressmayer, Mr. AL in third person to the Duke of Sussex, Portland Place, 1830 Jun 14 (Box 2, Folder 113)
      - Accompanied by AL in third person to T. L. Pettigrew, n.p., n.d.
  - "R"
    - Reich, J. H. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, [n.p.], [1822] (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Renouard, Antoine Augustin, 1765-1853
      - ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Paris, 1826 Feb 20 (Box 2, Folder 115)
      - ALS to T.J. Pettigrew, 10 Arundel St., 1829 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Rio Maior, comte de. 2 LS in French to the Duke of Sussex, Lisbon, 1814 Jan, Apr (Box 2, Folder 117)
      Congratulations on the return of peace.
    - Rodd, Mrs. Tremayne (Rennell). AL to the Duke of Sussex, Wimpole Street, 1830 Dec 14 (Box 2, Folder 118)
      Sends Geography of Herodotus by her father.
    - Roy, Rammohun, 1772-1833. ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, 125 Regent Street, 1831 May 28 (Box 2, Folder 119)
      Inquires after the Duke of Sussex's health.
    - Royal Academy of Music. 3 Letters to the Duke of Sussex on its founding, signed by Lord Burgerch, Sir A. F. Barnard and J. Murray, Pall Mall, 1822 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Royal Highland School Society. Resolutions of sympathy with the Duke of Sussex on death of George IV and hope for patronage of William IV, signed by Viscount Goderich (later Lord Ripon), Freemason's Hall, 1830 Jul 8 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - "S"
    - Sabrine, Sir Edward, 1788-1883. AL to the Duke of Sussex, Portland Place, 1825 Aug 8 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Salisbury, James Brownlow William Gascoyne-Cecil, 2d marquis of, 1791- 1868. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Grafton Street, [n.y.] May 22 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Scaum, George. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, 4 Old North Street, 1827 Jun 19 (Box 2, Folder 124)
      Seeks subscription for intended work.
    - Scottish Hospital and Corporation. Letter to the Duke of Sussex, signed by Lord Glenorchy (later Marquis of Breadalbane), Scottish Hall, 1823 Apr 2 (Box 2, Folder 125)
      An invitation.
    - Shepherd, Henry. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, London, [1824] Jan 16 (Box 2, Folder 126)
    - Skinner, George, ca. 1796-1872. AL to the Duke of Sussex, Jesus Coll. Cambridge, 1830 Jun 10 (Box 2, Folder 127)
      Presents his translation of the Psalms.
    - Smith, Sir Sidney, 1764-1840. LS to the Duke of Sussex, Paris, 1817 Apr 12 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    - Smith, William. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Carbellow near Glasgow, 1830 Aug 2 (Box 2, Folder 129)
      Sends a book on Scottish history.
    - Society for the Encouragement of Industry. Letter to the Duke of Sussex, King's Head, Poultry, 1829 Nov 10 (Box 2, Folder 130)
      Invitation to become President.
    - Society in Scotland for Propagating Christian Knowledge
      - 2 ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Edinburgh, 1827, 1829 (Box 2, Folder 131)
        Accompanied by extract from the minutes, with complimentary letter, Edinburgh
    - Somerset, C. ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Royal Institution, 1827 Jun 4 (Box 2, Folder 132)
      Thanks for first parts of Bibliotheca Sussexiana.
    - Spagnoletti, Paolo, 1768-1834. Announcement, printed and signed, to the Duke of Sussex, 17 Arundel St., 1830 May 31 (Box 2, Folder 133)
      Annual benefit concert at King's Theatre.
    - Spencean Philanthropists Committee of Distribution, 1816 Aug 17 (Box 2, Folder 134)
      Sends a copy of "Christian Policy."
    - Staines, Sir Thomas, 1776-1830. AL to the Duke of Sussex, Chatham, 1830 Jun 4 (Box 2, Folder 135)
      Two boxes, 1000 and 500, of Havana cigars.
    - Stewart, John, fl. 1820-1850
      - 7 ALS to T. J. Pettigrew, London, Swaffham, and Sydersterne, 1831-34 (Box 2, Folder 136)
        Seeks, and gains, publication and preferment.
      - 3 ALS to the Duke of Sussex, Swaffham, 1826-31 (Box 2, Folder 137)